Further Training and main Projects

Master in NextJs => the React framework for production. NextJs gives us an excellent development experience with the functions I needed for production such as: SSR and static hybrid rendering, which combining it with TypeScript, can achieve impressive results, getting to create apps with exceptionally good functioning and finish both in Front and Backend.

Ecommerce - Full Stack: https://solidcamper.herokuapp.com/

Complete and quite large application for the management and sale of products. Full development with collections, maintenance, loading, and optimizations for SEO, deployed in Heroku.

Front-End Technologies: ReactJS 18 typed with TS, **NextJS** 12, created with **Vite** and YARN Packaging, Emotion and Material UI for the styling making a fully responsive and functional web

Back-End Technologies: DB with MongoDB and Docker containers loading images in **Cloudinary**. Next AUTH for the authentication and Middleware's to protect routes. Creating the whole CRUD and the API REST with NodeJS.

React Master + Unit & integration Tests => for functional components with Fernando Herrera, working with hooks, custom Hooks, Redux, Fetch meanwhile using Backend technology as NodeJS, MongoDB, Docker, and Firestone.

Calendar - Full Stack: https://mern-calendar-dmateu.herokuapp.com/

Front-End Technologies: **ReactJS** 18, **Redux**, **MomentJS**, **Bootstrap**, Vite with **YARN** Packaging and **Bootstrap** for the styling.

Back-End Technologies: DB with **MongoDB** and **Cloudfare** for the performance and security for the site. Express and NodeJS as Backend Language, Next AUTH for the <u>authentication</u> validations and finally Unit Tests with **JEST**.

Crypto Currency - Front End: https://cryptos-och870fqq-danielmateu.vercel.app/

Technologies: **ReactJS** 18, **Styled Components**, **VITE** and **npm** packages. Building our own Hooks and connecting to **cryptocompare's** API.

Node: From Cero to Expert Udemy Course => In this NodeJS module I learned how to create backend servers, uploading, and managing files on the server, building applications using sockets, authenticating users with JWT, and creating REST services as well as applications in the console itself.

Education

- Frontend Web Developer at IT Academy (Barcelona Activa). After the covid situation I decided to redirect myself through the IT Sector, absorbing new knowledge as web development using technologies such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript and frameworks like Bootstrap, Sass, Angular and React libraries. During the bootcamp held at the IT Academy, I discovered this new world that is always on the move and my decision is not to stop learning to improve my soft and hard skills in this incredible world!
- 2011 English at Official School of Languages in Vall Hebrón, Barcelona.
- 2007 Audiovisual Technician at Polytechnic Center Villar in Barcelona (CPV)

Languages

English - C1 Cambridge First certificate 2008-2010

Spanish - Native

Catalan - Native

Extensive knowledge of computer applications in the Windows and Mac environment.

Constant work with audio, video and image editors as Logic Pro, Final Cut, Pack Adobe Creative Cloud

Work Experience during the last years

Niza Cars Rent a Car (2019 – 2022) as Supervisor and coordinator of the head office in Barcelona. Currently one of the best valued offices in the car rental sector, according to Google. My functions inside the office are based on accompanying the team to solve any unforeseen situation and helping my colleagues to better achieve the results that the company expects of them.

Sell by tell Group (2018 – 2019) as a specialist customer service phone agent for hardware and software Google Projects.

SIXT Rent a Car (2017 - 2018) as a sales agent and customer service. With good numbers in reference to sales and excellent feedback of my clients and colleagues.

Interests and other particularities

I consider myself a hardworking person with attitude and good skills in the workplace. I am looking for a position in a job that makes me grow as a professional and the best work environment, love to travel and discover new worlds and cultures. Music & Art lover, and an open mind person.

Currently studying German at the official language School of the Vall Hebron, in Barcelona. Fully convinced that proficiency in languages opens the door to everywhere.

On the other hand, would like to add that my incorporation can be immediate, and my work adaptation is usually fast.

For further information about my recent developing work, or me:

https://github.com/danielmateu/

https://daniel-mateu-porfolio.vercel.app/

https://www.linkedin.com/in/daniel-mateu-pardo/